const dummy = [
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 1,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 2,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 3,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 4,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 5,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
    ],
  },
];


export const ch1mcqs = [
  {
    numb: 1,
    question: "ax<sup>2</sup>+bx+c, where c≠0 is called__.",
    options: [
      "linear equation",
      "Quadratic equation",
      "Cubic equation",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Quadratic equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 2,
    question: "If a&equals;0 in ax<sup>2</sup>+bx+c then it becomes__.",
    options: [
      "Quadratic equation",
      "Cubic equation",
      "Linear equation",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Linear equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 3,
    question: "Completing square is a method to solve__.",
    options: [
      "Quadratic equation",
      "Cubic equation",
      "Linear equation",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Quadratic equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 4,
    question: "Solution set of 5x<sup>2</sup>&equals;30x is__.",
    options: ["{6}", "{0}", "{25}", "{0,6}"],
    answer: "{0,6}",
  },
  {
    numb: 5,
    question: "Standard form of Quadratic equation is__.",
    options: [
      "ax<sup>2</sup>+bx",
      "ax<sup>2</sup>+c",
      "ax<sup>2</sup>+bx+c",
      "bx+c",
    ],
    answer: "ax<sup>2</sup>+bx+c",
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "__ is quadratic formula.",
    options: [
      "x &equals; (-b ± &Sqrt;(b<sup>2</sup> - 4ac)) / 2a",
      "x &equals; (-b + &Sqrt;(b<sup>2</sup> - 4ac)) / 2a",
      "x &equals; (-b - &Sqrt;(b<sup>2</sup> - 4ac)) / 2a",
      "x &equals; (b ± &Sqrt;(b<sup>2</sup> - 4ac)) / 2a",
    ],
    answer: "x &equals; (-b ± &Sqrt;(b<sup>2</sup> - 4ac)) / 2a",
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Linear factors of x<sup>2</sup>-8x+15 are__.",
    options: [
      "(x+5) and (x-3)",
      "(x-5) and (x+5)",
      "(x+5) and (x+3)",
      "(x-5) and (x-3)",
    ],
    answer: "(x-5) and (x-3)",
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question:
      "An equation which remains unchanged when x is replaced by 1/x is called__.",
    options: [
      "Exponential equation",
      "Radical equation",
      "Reciprocal equation",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Reciprocal equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question:
      "An equation of the type 3<sup>x</sup>+3<sup>2-x</sup>+4&equals;0 is a/an.",
    options: [
      "Exponential equation",
      "Radical equation",
      "Reciprocal equation",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Exponential equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The solution set of x<sup>2</sup>-16&equals;0 is__.",
    options: ["{±4}", "{±2}", "4", "0"],
    answer: "{±4}",
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The solution set of 25x<sup>2</sup>-1 &equals; 0 is__.",
    options: ["{±5}", "{±5i}", "{±1/5}", "{±1/5i}"],
    answer: "{±1/5}",
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question:
      "An equation of the form 5&Sqrt;x<sup>2</sup>+2 &equals; 0 is called:",
    options: [
      "Exponential equation",
      "Radical equation",
      "Reciprocal equation",
      "None of these",
    ],
    answer: "Radical equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Competing square is a technique to solve__.",
    options: [
      "Exponential equation",
      "Radical equation",
      "Reciprocal equation",
      "Quadratic equation",
    ],
    answer: "Quadratic equation",
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "The number of terms in a standard quadratic equation can be__.",
    options: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
    answer: "3",
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "The solution set of &Sqrt;(3x+7) = 2x+3 is__.",
    options: ["{-2}", "{-2, -1/4}", "{-1/4}", "None of these"],
    answer: "{-1/4}",
  },
];

export const ch2mcqs = [
      {
        numb: 1,
        question: "Discriminant of quadratic equation is:",
        options: [
          "b<sup>2</sup>-4a",
          "b<sup>2</sup>-4ac",
          "2a",
          "None of these"
        ],
        answer: "b<sup>2</sup>-4ac"
      },
      {
        numb: 2,
        question: "Discriminant of x<sup>2</sup>-3x+3=0",
        options: [
          "21",
          "-3",
          "-21",
          "2"
        ],
        answer: "-3"
      },
      {
        numb: 3,
        question: "If discriminant is positive and perfect square then roots are:",
        options: [
          "Real",
          "Unequal",
          "Rational and equal",
          "Rational and unequal"
        ],
        answer: "Rational and equal"
      },
      {
        numb: 4,
        question: "If discriminant is positive and not perfect square then roots are:",
        options: [
          "Rational and unequal",
          "Irrational and unequal",
          "Irrational and equal",
          "None of these"
        ],
        answer: "Irrational and unequal"
      },
      {
        numb: 5,
        question: "If discriminant is equal to zero then roots are:",
        options: [
          "Rational and equal",
          "Rational and unequal",
          "Irrational and equal",
          "Irrational and unequal"
        ],
        answer: "Rational and equal"
      },
      {
        numb: 6,
        question: "If discriminant is less than zero then roots are:",
        options: [
          "Real",
          "Rational",
          "Irrational",
          "Imaginary"
        ],
        answer: "Imaginary"
      },
      {
        numb: 7,
        question: "Roots of x<sup>2</sup>-5x+5&equals; are__.",
        options: [
          "Rational and equal",
          "Irrational and unequal",
          "Imaginary",
          "None of these"
        ],
        answer: "Irrational and unequal"
      },
      {
        numb: 8,
        question: "discriminant of x<sup>2</sup>+8x+16&equals;0 is:",
        options: [
          "16",
          "8",
          "0",
          "1"
        ],
        answer: "0"
      },
      {
        numb: 9,
        question: "Roots of (k+3)x<sup>2</sup>-2(k+1)x-(k+1)&equals=0 are equal then value of k is:",
        options: [
          "-2",
          "-1",
          "-2,-1",
          "0"
        ],
        answer: "-2,-1"
      },
      {
        numb: 10,
        question: "Sum of the roots of equation 3x<sup>2</sup>-5x+7=0 is:",
        options: [
          "-5/3",
          "3/5",
          "7/3",
          "5/3"
        ],
        answer: "5/3"
      },
      {
        numb: 11,
        question: "Product of the roots of equation 3x<sup>2</sup>-5x+7=0 is:",
        options: [
          "-5/3",
          "3/5",
          "7/3",
          "5/3"
        ],
        answer: "7/3"
      },
      {
        numb: 12,
        question: "Product of the roots of equation ax<sup>2</sup>+bx+c=0 is:",
        options: [
          "-a/b",
          "c/a",
          "b/a",
          "-c/a"
        ],
        answer: "c/a"
      },
      {
        numb: 13,
        question: "If the sum of the squares of the roots of the equation 4x<sup>2</sup> + 3kx + k<sup>2</sup>=0 is unity then what is the value of k?",
        options: [
          "±4",
          "4",
          "-4",
          "3/4"
        ],
        answer: "±4"
      },
      {
        question: "Quadratic equation with roots 3 and 4 is:",
        numb: 14,
        options: [
          "x<sup>2</sup>-3x+4=0",
          "x<sup>2</sup>-4x+3=0",
          "x<sup>2</sup>-7x+12=0",
          "x<sup>2</sup>-12x+7=0"
        ],
        answer: "x<sup>2</sup>-7x+12=0"
      },
      {
        numb: 15,
        question: "If we divide the polynomial 5x<sup>4</sup> + x<sup>3</sup> -3x by x-2 then the remainder is:",
        options: [
          "41",
          "22",
          "85",
          "82"
        ],
        answer: "82"
      },
      {
        numb: 16,
        question: "Sum of cube roots of unity is:",
        options: [
          "0",
          "1",
          "-1",
          "3"
        ],
        answer: "0"
      },
      {
        numb: 17,
        question: "Product of cube roots of unity is:",
        options: [
          "0",
          "1",
          "-1",
          "3"
        ],
        answer: "1"
      },
      {
        numb: 18,
        question: "The nature of roots of the equation ax<sup>2</sup> + bx + c = 0 is determined by:",
        options: [
          "sum of the roots",
          "product of the roots",
          "synthetic division",
          "discriminant"
        ],
        answer: "discriminant"
      },
      {
        numb: 19,
        question: "Roots of -1 are:",
        options: [
          "-1, -&omega;, -&omega;<sup>2</sup>",
          "-1, &omega;, -&omega;<sup>2</sup>",
          "-1, &omega;, &omega;<sup>2</sup>",
          "1, -&omega;, -&omega;<sup>2</sup>",
        ],
        answer: "-1, &omega;, &omega;<sup>2</sup>"
      },
      {
        numb: 20,
        question: "Two square roots of unity are:",
        options: [
          "1, -1",
          "1, &omega;",
          "1, -&omega;",
          "&omega;, -&omega;<sup>2</sup>"
        ],
        answer: "1, -1"
      },
];


export const ch3mcqs = [
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 1,
        question: "A relation between two quantities of the same kind is called:",
        options: ["Proportion", "Ratio", "Variation", "None of these"],
        answer: "Ratio",
      },
      {
        numb: 2,
        question: "Unit of ratio is:",
        options: ["Meter", "Kg", "Second", "No unit"],
        answer: "No unit",
      },
      {
        numb: 3,
        question: "Equivalence of two ratios is called:",
        options: ["Proportion", "Ratio", "Variation", "None of these"],
        answer: "Proportion",
      },
      {
        numb: 4,
        question: "What is the value of a, if the ratios a+3:7+a and 3:5 are equal:",
        options: ["13", "10", "5", "2"],
        answer: "2",
      },
      {
        numb: 5,
        question: "In proportion statement a:b=c:d, a,d are called:",
        options: ["means", "extremes", "ratios", "None of these"],
        answer: "",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 6,
        question: "Value of x in proportion 8-x:11-x::16-x:25-x is__.",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 7,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 8,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 9,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 10,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
    ],
  },
  {
    mcq: [
      {
        numb: 11,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 12,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 13,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 14,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
      {
        numb: 15,
        question: "",
        options: ["", "", "", ""],
        answer: "",
      },
    ],
  },
];